Guide to the Morris and Dorothy Margolin film collection, 1947-1982 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Reel 5: France, Italy, 1955
  street scenes, bicyclists, pedestrians crossing street
  Dorothy walks on cobblestone street, café in background
  Dorothy pretends to hitchhike next to sign: "N5 Fontainebleau 8 Paris 66"
  exteriors of Fontainebleau, Dorothy walks toward palace
  interiors of Fontainebleau, including close-ups on artworks; some too dark to see
  view of Fontainebleau from cafe
  woman wearing a hat approaches a horse on the street, pets it; others follow suit
  street scenes, shot from above; pedestrians and traffic
  long shot of Dorothy, walks toward camera; Miramar [Hotel] in background
  Dorothy walks toward camera, ocean and rocks in the background
  Dorothy skips back toward water
  close-up on the Miramar [Hotel]
  close up: Jean Patou
  traffic cop directs traffic
  Kodak store in background, Dorothy nearby; pedestrians and traffic in foreground
  Dorothy considers shop offerings
  Dorothy walks toward camera, casino in background, pans over to La Maison Basque
  Dorothy poses against fence, shops and ocean in background
  Dorothy outside of Casino Bellevue, walks toward camera
  Dorothy passes small art gallery, Exposition Moreau; stops to show off the paintings
  Dorothy at café table with huge tray of seafood
  Dorothy walks by alley that looks onto ocean
  uniformed man outside of building
  Dorothy in hotel lobby or restaurant?
  beach scenes, bikinis, includes shots of Dorothy
  Dorothy goes for a swim
  Necresco Hotel in Nice, France
  shots of cityscape across the water
  cars parked along street near ocean, sign: "Frontière"
  bumper to bumper traffic at Italian border
  sign: "Arret obligatoire des vehicules allant en Italie"
  narrow Italian street
  Dorothy wanders through crowded city square
  tops of ornate buildings in Genova?
  Dorothy? stands next to large columns
  sidewalk scenes
  aerial views of city, Christopher Columbus statue?
  aerial views of harbor, ocean, apartment buildings
  aerial view of horse (or donkey?) drawn cart
  ocean dotted with sailboats
  sidewalk scene
  two men gesture, point
  pans to café tables and chairs on open street near small inlet filled with boats
  Dorothy wanders around, interacts with the two men
  one of the men points camera toward Morris's camera
  three men stand around, discussing
  Dorothy looks at fabric? being sold at a stand
  boats rocking in the inlet
  Dorothy walks along street; boats, buildings, water in the background
  Dorothy poses with the two men by the water
  Morris and Dorothy, holding hands, walk toward water; joined by one of the men, they shake hands and pose
  scenic shots of water, buildings and hills
  Dorothy and the two men sitting at café table
  Dorothy climbs into a donkey drawn cart
  the two men sit at the café table
  Morris talks to someone on the steps of the Monte Carlo Casino
  Morris shows empty pockets and walks down the stairs
  exteriors of the Monte Carlo Casino
  Dorothy waves from parking lot
  view of the cityscape
  Dorothy walks along, stopping across the street from the Carlton
  large promenade near beach
  people gather at tourist site? Dorothy in background
  unidentified church, Dorothy on street below it
  sign: "La Provence"
  quiet city square
  signs on awning: "Hotel de France / L'Auberge de France"
  police officer? stands near row of cars
  Dorothy sits at café, smokes a cigarette, waiter comes by
  Dorothy walks out of L'Hotel de Paris et de la Poste in Sens, France
  sign: "Boucherie Chevaline"
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (850 ft.) (Box 1)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 23:29) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 23:29) (Box 1)
- Reel 6: Spain, S.S. Queen Elizabeth, 1955
  Talgo train at San Sebastian station
  train ride from San Sebastian to Madrid: mountains, valleys, towns, railroad tracks
  tank with "San Sebastian" written on side
  Dorothy leaves restaurant near park in Madrid
  exteriors of Prado Museum; Dorothy exits with books
  Palace Hotel, roundabout
  Dorothy walks to sidewalk and toward camera
  Charles and Emma Fish; Emma, Spanish-Hungarian-Jewish "gal," Dorothy, and friend goof around, dance, take a bow
  exteriors of El Escorial
  Dorothy purchases souvenir from street vendor, climbs into car
  long shot of El Escorial, surrounding landscape
  Spanish girl seated on rocks
  view of El Escorial
  bullfight; includes a few crowd shots
  Dorothy, Emma and friend exit arena
  landscape shots, intercut with shots of crowd leaving
  Dorothy waits outside of stagecoach
  exteriors of Royal Palace of Madrid
  Plaza Major; street scenes
  villagers stand along side of road, looking at camera
  villagers do laundry outdoors
  sign: "A Madrid 5km"
  man walks toward group with dog
  Dorothy poses with villagers on the side of the road
  Romani? family walks alongside covered wagon
  Avenida de José Antonio
  street scenes, including street vendors
  architecture, including post office building
  entrance to metro
  sign: "Puerto del Sol"
  street scenes, Dorothy walks toward camera
  street scenes of Toledo
  exteriors of Toledo Cathedral
  uniformed man approaches camera
  young boy in traditional garb walks up hill toward camera
  more street scenes of Toledo, many including Dorothy
  Dorothy has wine with guide in main square of Toledo
  Colmar store
  street scenes in Madrid
  rural Spanish village, barren landscape
  sign: "Toledo"
  ruins of the Spanish Civil War
  bridge over river
  views of Toledo from overlook
  Dorothy climbs into car; tour guide at car door
  more views of Toledo
  Morris with Spanish women in front of shops
  Dorothy and Morris in front of synagogue in Toledo
  sign: "Sinagoga del Transito"
  street vendor with donkey
  Dorothy on tree-lined path, uniformed men avoid the camera
  sign: "House of El Greco"
  narrow street scenes, including donkeys
  Dorothy and tour guide walk toward camera
  Queen Elizabeth ship
  Dorothy lounges inside
  Dorothy on deck, adjusts headscarf
  ocean behind boat
  Morris lounges on the deck, waves, walk towards camera
  Dorothy waves from deck; sign: "1st Class Passengers Only" in front of her
  Morris points at smokestack on deck
  Dorothy lounges on deck
  people working on deck of ocean liner
  high angle shot of Dorothy reading on deck
  Dorothy and friends? lounging and drinking tea
  friends on board
  New York City, Statue of Liberty and harbor from the boat
  Dorothy on deck
  Queen Elizabeth at dock, unloading cargo
  New York dock, cars
  - Reversal original, 16mm, so., co., reel 1 of 1, (900 ft.) (Box 1)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 22:21) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 22:21) (Box 1)
- Reel 32: Quebec, Canada, December 1955
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (500 ft.) (Box 4)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: est. 13:53) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: est. 13:53) (Box TBD)
- Reel 7: Puerto Rico, Villa Rica, 1958
  sign: "4 Dormitorios Amueblados y Decorados por Patio Shop," in ground outside of building
  bungalows
  three men stand in street, looking at partially built bungalows
  cow in neighborhood, the men go over and pet it
  sign: "3 Dormitorios Amueblados y Decorados por Patio Shop"
  man stands in front of partially built structures, points camera at Morris's camera
  pans over landscape of partially built structures
  sign: "Nuevos Modelos de Casas Villa Rica Véalos Ahora! desde $8,990"
  exterior of Villa Rica sales office
  landscapes, including neighborhoods, streets
  close-up on poster, blurry
  monument: "A la memoria de Ramon Emeterio Betances"
  billboard: HNAS Davila Supermarket
  billboard: Casa Modelo Villa Rica
  billboard: Oficina de Ventas
  houses captured from moving car
  views of the construction area
  neon sign: Caribe Hilton
  tourists at hotel pool and beach, including ocean scenes
  flamingos
  Morris stands like a flamingo among the birds
  landscape and ocean from plane window
  plane lands
  people prepare to disembark, underexposed and dark
  travelers disembark from airplane at St. Thomas-Virgin Islands
  locals unload luggage from plane
  Caribair plane
  sign: "Welcome to St. Thomas Virgin Islands, U.S.A. Be sure to visit St. John and St. Croix"
  Caribair plane and stairs on tarmac
  Dorothy and daughters? pose under "Welcome" sign
  sign: too dark to read
  travelers sit in terminal
  group of (mostly) women look out at scenic view
  interior shots of a shop? underexposed and dark
  locals at harbor, fellow travelers mingle
  produce market at the harbor
  Dorothy walks toward camera
  donkey carries cargo down street
  large house
  golf course, close-up on someone setting up a shot
  group of men play golf
  golfers buy or receive? fruit from young man
  golfers peel and eat fruit
  Morris walks from golf cart, rolls up pant legs, and prepares to swing; golfs
  city square, street scenes
  unidentified church?
  San Juan National Historic Site Visitor Center
  sign: "Visitor Center San Juan National Historic Site / U.S. Department of the Interior National Park Service"
  parking lot near Visitor Center
  fellow travelers waiting in parking lot
  interior of Visitor Center?
  women at golf course
  man stands next to car
  sign: "Caribair"
  group of travelers waiting at airport, underexposed and dark
  sign: Pan American World Airways, underexposed and dark
  fellow travelers read newspapers, underexposed and dark
  poster: "The Virgin Islands by Caribair St. Crois St. John St. Thomas Now Also to St. Maarten, N.W.I."
  technicians? near plane on tarmac
  group approaches plane, poses outside, and boards
  Morris and unknown woman pose in front of plane, wave, and board
  interior of plane
  license plate: Tropical Playground T-116 Virgin Islands
  aerial view of town and ocean
  group at restaurant, underexposed and dark
  woman in bathing suit climbing onto and then off of boat
  tourists at hotel pool and beach
  series of swimmers jump from diving board
  unidentified church
  group walks away from Farmacia la Esperanza
  houses
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (600 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 16:34) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 16:34) (Box 1)
- Reel 8: Italy, 1959
  Includes narration and music. Structured as a story about the travels of a Simca, their rental car.
  Dorothy walks past young man getting water from pump, poses
  Dorothy sits at sidewalk table at café
  sidewalk and street scenes
  close-up of church facade
  Dorothy walks out of restaurant?
  sidewalk and street scenes, including produce stand
  Dorothy gets directions from man with a newspaper
  Dorothy at produce stand
  unidentified cathedral
  Dorothy at newsstand near cathedral
  houses on hillside, street scene
  harbor, including docked boats
  shops and street scene
  Dorothy climbs into Simca car, waving
  close-up on license plate of car
  sign: Villa d'Este
  car on shaded street
  another Villa d'Este sign
  landscape shot pans to car on shaded street
  boat in harbor
  Lake Como and environs
  Dorothy walks through garden at Villa d'Este
  small group of women walk toward parked car, the Simca?
  cars drive down narrow street toward camera
  Milan Cathedral, with plenty of pigeons outside
  Dorothy and fellow travelers
  building and parking lot
  Dorothy and friends walk toward Museo Teatrale
  sign: Museo Teatrale
  advertisement for La Boheme at Teatro alla Scala
  Milan City Centre: shops, Dorothy and friends, street scenes, fountain
  exterior of arena in Verona
  street scene
  advertisement for Arena Verona
  banner: "Arena di Verona - La Forza del Destino - Il Trovatore - Faust"; pans down to street scene
  buildings, including Rolex sign
  shops, narrow street
  clock tower, street scene
  statue fountain
  Dorothy outside of a cathedral? underexposed
  Verona city gate
  street scenes, including street performer
  statues on building
  Dorothy sitting on bench in park, near fountain
  exterior of cathedral
  directional sign: Roma, Arezzo, Firenze, Il Campo, Duomo
  woman walks by eating ice cream
  narrow curved street, car drives toward camera
  sign: "Costa Larga"; pans down to street scene
  Dorothy walks toward "Ristorante," pans up to apartment buildings
  Dorothy walks away from Ristorante, toward camera
  city square
  two women stand by fence near body of water
  sign: "San Marino"
  signs for restaurants, hotels
  shots of Dorothy at Guaita fortress
  aerial shot of countryside from Guaita
  Dorothy with fortress in background, looking at guidebook
  Dorothy at outdoor café table
  two women walking up cobblestone street
  Dorothy with countryside in background, Vespa? in foreground
  Dorothy walks down narrow cobblestone side street
  Dorothy near signs
  streets crowded with shoppers, including Dorothy
  statue and tower
  Italian countryside
  crowded street, two uniformed men walk toward camera
  guards
  flag
  sign: visas
  traffic cop directs (very little) traffic
  guards near wall: S. Marino Italia
  sunbathers on rocks at water
  beach hotel and many umbrellas
  beachgoers on rocks at water
  water crashing against rocks, people swimming
  bikini-clad sunbather reading
  Dorothy puts on swimming cap and gets in the water
  rocks, waves and beachgoers
  marina with fortress in background, colorful apartment buildings, café chairs, boats
  men walk by with luggage cart, boats in background
  two women with a baby at café
  marina, boats
  colorful apartment buildings, pans down to boats
  crowded street scene with sidewalk vendors, buildings
  aerial view with water, buildings, mountains
  ocean at sunset, boats and pier?
  aerial view of water, town, mountains
  colorful beachside hotel
  sunbathers under umbrellas near hotel
  city square, people gathered around outdoor theatre?
  more shots of city square, including monks? and nurses?
  monks? or friars? talking, sign in background: Otello
  three women stand outside of souvenir? shop
  men sit at sidewalk tables
  close-ups of buildings on square
  crowded (narrow) street scenes, near the city square
  close-ups of couple on small balcony, architecture
  adolescents hanging out, architecture
  city square, Dorothy? crosses square and climbs steps to unidentified church
  shots of church, Dorothy? enters
  make-shift newspaper stand outside of church, headline about Eisenhower
  Dorothy poses near well
  Florence skyline from across Arno River; Dorothy enters frame, poses
  view down the Arno River, including Ponte Santa Trinita and Ponte Vecchio
  close-up of jewelry in window, pulls back to show Dorothy looking in at them
  more close-ups of a jewelry window display
  long shot of stylish woman in profile, baby toddles around and falls in background
  shots, including close-ups, of stylish woman posing, model?
  street scenes, some include Dorothy
  Dorothy walks over to fenced bust of Benvenuto Cellini
  sign: "A Benvenuto Cellini Maestro / gli orafi di Firenze"
  Dorothy by bust, points, poses on bridge, sits on curb
  Dorothy window-shops, camera pans to street, including woman with camera
  Dorothy at window display of jewelry, points
  Arno River, buildings, bridge
  group waits in front of bus
  close-ups of exterior of basilica Santa Maria del Fiore, glimpse of the crowd
  woman in dress poses, model?
  street scenes, including street vendors, street sweeper, horse-drawn carriage
  crowd waiting outside building
  Dorothy talks to stylish woman near car, model?
  city square, including horse-drawn carriage
  Dorothy walks out of shop
  more exteriors of the basilica of Santa Maria del Fiore, including the dome
  crowd, people pointing up
  street scene, including traffic cop
  exterior of Albergo Excelsior Italia, Dorothy talks to man in white uniform
  smaller crowd outside of previously-seen building
  directional sign: Pisa, Livorno; roads
  countryside, bales of hay
  leaning tower of Pisa and environs
  street scenes near leaning tower, nuns and monks walk by line of souvenir stalls
  more shots of leaning tower of Pisa
  from tower, Dorothy walks toward the camera
  buildings nearby leaning tower of Pisa, and the tower again
  Dorothy waits in line at street cart near base of leaning tower of Pisa
  group of monks walking away from camera
  street scenes near leaning tower of Pisa, including priest riding bicycle
  men in jester suits guard passageway
  shots of St. Peter's Square, Vatican City
  priest takes photograph for family
  close-up on statue
  young woman climbs onto motor scooter with young man
  exteriors of St. Peter's Basilica, complete with tour buses
  obelisk
  fountain
  columned promenade near St. Peter's Basilica
  people exiting St. Peter's Basilica? including a Buddhist? monk and a fancifully uniformed man
  close-up: Musei Vaticani
  people entering St. Peter's Basilica? man perched near entrance
  close-up on sign for Monumenti Musei e Gallerie Pontifici
  people walk along Vatican wall, past street vendors
  sign: "Only five hours from Rome visit Israel the land of the Bible"
  buildings, street scene; nun in foreground before frame pans up
  Vatican wall and Musei Vaticani archway with statues above, bus drives by, people come and go
  Dorothy holds picture, stands in front of Vatican wall?
  shot of Dorothy on sidewalk, under café umbrellas
  pans to include sidewalk and café
  underexposed shot, hard to see
  skyline with palm tree in foreground, domes behind
  Dorothy walks down curved outdoor steps
  church? Dorothy enters frame, walking down steps
  shot of Dorothy sitting on steps with church? behind her
  Dorothy approaches and interacts with a group of people, perhaps a Jewish-Italian family? in rural setting
  women hoe hay, other farmwork
  woman walks toward building carrying container on head
  chicken and her chicks
  donkey with cart, occupied by small boy
  men hang out under brick structure
  woman walks down steps
  street scene with café tables, woman carrying cargo on head, uniformed man
  Dorothy (in two different outfits) outside unidentified building, probably in Rome
  - Reversal original, 16mm, so., co., reel 1 of 1, (1150 ft.) (Box 1)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 31:21) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 31:21) (Box 1)
- Reel 9: Majorca, Barcelona, 1959
  Includes music, but no narration.
  harbor
  boats
  historic buildings
  museum
  bullfight at stadium
  donkey cart
  people
  street vendors
  stores
  windmills
  farm
  boy milking cow
  tourists on beach
  people in traditional clothing, playing instruments and performing traditional dances
  Barcelona
  cars
  church
  cathedrals
  horse cart
  buildings
  sign: Barcelona
  sign: Ritz
  last scene: exterior of Ritz Hotel
  - Reversal original, 16mm, so., co., reel 1 of 1, (500 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 13:52) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 13:52) (Box 1)
- Reel 10: S.S. New Amsterdam, France, 1959
  New York City 5th Street Pier
  Holland-American Line pier
  aerial view of tugboat
  S.S. New Amsterdam ocean liner
  people on the S.S. New Amsterdam
  Southampton docks
  France
  sign: "Vernaison"
  market
  sign: "Le Coq Hardi"
  park
  taxi
  Paris
  military tank in the middle of a city square near the Eiffel Tower
  sign: "Exposition Napoleon III Magenta Solferino Le Prince Imperial"
  Louvre
  sign: "Place Vendôme"
  monuments
  Maxim's
  sign: "Avenue des Champs-élysées"
  cafés
  restaurants
  Southern France - the Riviera
  Carlton Hotel
  beach
  outdoor vendors
  sailors
  esplanade
  Martinez
  aerial view of city
  garden
  people at beach
  sign: "Carlton"
  gay male couple?
  Israeli flag
  sign: "Red Roc"
  seaside resort
  sign: "Beau Rivage Palace Hotel"
  Switzerland
  building flying Swiss flag
  mountains in background
  fields
  aerial view of mountain town
  sign: "Café Schutzhaus"
  snow, snowy rocks
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (975 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 27:10) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 27:10) (Box 1)
- Reel 11: Puerto Rico, Jamaica, 1959
  title card: "Islands in the Sun: Puerto Rico, Jamaica, St. Thomas"
  Dorothy and friends (possibly family?) sunbathing, hamming it up for the camera
  people relaxing in waterfalls
  underexposed, hard to see
  woman climbs into car
  funicular
  aerial views of lush landscape and ocean
  fellow travelers outside of hotel?
  British flag; probably in Jamaica
  lush landscape
  travelers climb into car outside of hotel?
  men ride bicycles, pull goats on a leash
  young girl on side of the road
  sign: "Jamaica Inn"
  palm tree and ocean
  resort, beach scenes
  street scenes, shot from a moving car
  monument
  houses, shot from a moving car
  uniformed man in front of constabulary station
  woman selling produce at roadside stand
  traffic jam? cars stopped, people gathered
  another shot of produce stand
  group standing outside of bus
  police car
  cars stationary on road
  people stand on the roadside, shot from inside a car
  woman carries a bundle on her head
  man rides by on donkey
  women carry baskets on their heads
  fellow traveler beside fenced garden
  fellow traveler in the middle of the road, vehicle approaches from behind
  sign: "JAA Bog Walk"
  shots of unidentified building with fenced garden in front
  shots of "Tom Cringle's Cotton Tree," including sign
  cart hauling palm fronds, shot from behind
  street scenes, shot from inside car
  women waving straw hats
  sidewalk and street scenes, including fellow travelers
  directional sign: "Victoria Crafts Market"
  street and sidewalk scenes
  group of children walk toward the camera
  young girl and father pose for camera
  young boys play on the sidewalk, hamming it up for the camera
  street scenes from car, including traffic cops
  fellow travelers stand beneath sign: "Welcome to Victoria Crafts Market: The All-Jamaican Shopping Centre"
  boats on the water, at dock
  woman embellishing hats
  advertisement: Welcome to Jamaica See the Exciting Mid-Day Native Floor Show at New Bamboo Club
  fellow travelers climb into car
  Dorothy poses for camera in garden
  Dorothy and friend pose in front of flower garden that spells out "Welcome to Hope"
  garden, flowers
  patio seating at restaurant, fellow travelers and other tourists drink, eat, dance
  Dorothy and friends balance drinks on their heads
  Dorothy and friends drink
  traditionally dressed Jamaican musicians play and dance for tourists on patio
  lots of dancing!
  man walks to car, stormy day
  life preserver: Arawak Hotel, Jamaica, B.W.I.
  exteriors of the Arawak Hotel
  fellow travelers sunbathe on the beach
  birds fly overhead
  Dorothy and fellow travelers walk from beach to hotel pool
  each poses with life preserver framing their face
  overexposed shot of ocean
  fellow travelers swimming in ocean
  boats in water: sailboat, glass bottom boat, etc.
  beach filled with beachgoers, pier
  pool at the Arawak Hotel?
  Dorothy? in swimming cap swims out to friend on raft
  the Margolins? runs out into ocean together, swims back to shore
  another couple does the same
  buffet meal
  hotel pool
  back to the mealtime
  sign: "670 New York"
  sign: "Avianca Colombian National Airway"
  shots of Avianca plane on tarmac
  interiors of plane, underexposed
  shots of clouds, propeller, sunset from airplane window
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (600 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 21:27) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 21:27) (Box 1)
- Reel 12: Aruba, 1962
  three people sitting in seats at an airport